libretti what is going on welcome to the
剧本 是怎么回事欢迎 的
second akivi tutorial basics video in
第二个akivi教程基础视频中
this video we're just gonna kind of
这个视频，我们只是会种
build on top of the last video so in the
建立在 最后一个视频 的顶部 ，这样的
last video we had this really basic
最后一个视频， 我们有这个基本的
application and what was happening was
应用程序和发生的事情是
they're just popping up with a simple
他们 只是弹出 一个简单的
hello world label but as we could see it
你好世界的标签，但我们可以看到它
was already resizable into you know
已经调整到你知道的水平
basically many different sizes so it
它基本上有很多不同的尺寸
would work on all kinds of different
将在各种 不同 的 工作
devices and screens and obviously we can
设备和屏幕 ，显然我们 可以
see that's already at least you can you
看到那已经 至少你可以
know kind of close the window and that
知道那种关闭窗口和
was about it I don't really have any
是关于它我 真的 没有
other I don't know uses for this other
其他我不知道 用于其他
than we just wanted to show some text
比我们只想 展示一些文字
now let's say we actually want to build
现在让我们说我们真的想要建立
a simple application and let's say the
一个简单的应用程序，让我们说
first screen is some sort of a login
第一个屏幕是某种登录
screen so how do we do that well first
那么我们该如何做好这件事
of all what's all that's happening so
所有这一切正在发生
far is we've got this ki V app class
远远是我们有这个 ki V应用程序类
here that we're inheriting from with a
在这里，我们继承了一个
simple key v class of our own we inherit
我们自己继承的简单关键v类
from there and then we define the build
从那里，然后我们定义 构建
and the only thing what's happening in
以及发生 的 唯一事情
our build is we're just returning a
我们的构建是我们 只是返回一个
label so that's all our app does is
标签，这是我们所有的应用程序所做的
returns a label now obviously that's a
现在 显然返回一个标签 ，这是一个
little impractical that's not really
这实际上不太实际
what we want to do so instead let's say
让我们说，我们想 要这样做
for now our app only has login screen so
现在我们的应用程序 只有登录屏幕
what we want to eventually return login
我们想要最终返回登录
screen okay so now we need to define
屏幕好，所以现在我们需要 定义
login screen there's no login screens
登录屏幕没有登录屏幕
that I know of with TV luckily for us
我很 幸运地 知道 我们的 电视
TVs has a few more things than on top of
电视还有其他一些东西
Pi game as far as you know kind of built
丕游戏只要 你知道那种 建
in things that you can use but I don't
在你可以使用的东西中， 但我不知道
believe login screen is one of them
相信登录屏幕就是其中之一
anyways we'll come on down whoops
无论如何，我们会降低 哎呀
wrong button come on down here now and
错了 按钮 现在 下来吧这里
now let's go ahead and define our login
现在让我们继续并定义我们的登录
screen now this is going to be a little
屏幕现在这将是一个小的
thicker than the last tutorial so stick
比上 一篇教程厚一些
with me but I'll do my best to explain
和我一起，但我会尽我所能解释
everything that I'm doing so first of
所有我 首先 做的事情
all we can leave this label import but
所有我们可以离开这个标签导入，但
now what we're going to actually do is
现在我们要实际做的是
we're going to bring in the layout so
我们将这样引入布局
first let me just type it from K v UI x
首先让我从K v UI x中输入它
dot grid layout we want to in
点网格布局我们想要在
poor capital G grid capital L layout uh
贫穷的资本 G电网资本L布局 呃
we'll leave that and the grid layout
我们将离开它和网格 布局
there's I think like five or six
我想有五 六个
different types of layouts and we'll
不同类型的布局， 我们会
kind of cover that those in a little bit
那种涵盖那些在一 点点
but basically the layouts are used their
但基本上布局被用于他们的
layout it's kind of like a from tkinter
布局它有点像tkinter
for example you had two major types of
例如你有两种主要的类型
layouts you had a grid layout and you
你有一个网格布局的布局
almost had like look at what the other
几乎 像 在看什么其他
one was it was more like a relative kind
一个是它更像是一种相对的种类
of layout and so grid layout you can
的布局和网格布局，你可以
imagine it's you know based on grids and
想象一下，你知道基于网格和
there's all kinds of different layouts
有各种 不同的布局
with keavy this is just one of them so
与 keavy 这只是 其中之一 ，所以
anyway we're going to use the grid
无论如何，我们要 使用网格
layout and then finally because it's a
布局 ，然后最终因为它是一个
login screen we need some way to
登录屏幕我们需要一些方法来
actually import her input rather text so
实际导入她的 输入，而 这样 的文字
next thing we're going to do is from a
接下来 我们 要做的是从 a
TV UI X dot text input we're going to
电视用户界面 X 点文本输入我们将 要
import capital T text capital I input
进口资本T文本我输入
and that really should be it I think we
那真的应该是我认为我们
might need to import the base key V but
可能需要导入基本密钥 V但是
I'm sure that's necessary here anyway
无论如何 ，我相信这是必要的
we'll see if we run into it so first
我们会看看我们 是否首先 遇到 它
what we're going to say is we're going
我们要说的是我们要走了
to call our class and obviously we need
打电话给 我们的 班级，显然我们需要
to name it login screen so I'm going to
为了命名它的登录屏幕，所以我要去
copy launch main class login screen and
复制启动 主类登录屏幕和
is there anything we want to inherit
有什么我们想要 继承
from well we want to inherit from grid
我们希望从网格继承
layout so this is your kind of back end
布局，所以这是你的那种 后端
stuff it's your back end layout so it's
这是你的后端布局，所以它是
not just like a simple class we want to
不仅仅是 我们想要 的简单 课程
actually we're going to inherit from
实际上我们要继承
this entire grid layout so I'm going to
这整个网格布局，所以我要去
copy that paste that in again if you're
复制 粘贴，如果你是
not comfortable with the idea of
不舒服的 想法
inheritance check out the crash course
继承检查崩溃过程
to object-oriented programming tutorial
到面向对象的程序设计教程
I have so a class login screen grid
我有一个类登录屏幕网格
layout and as you're probably familiar
布局和你可能很熟悉
with if you understand object-oriented
如果你明白面向对象的话
programming is the first class we're
编程是我们的第一堂课
going to write or the first uh sorry the
要写或第一个呃抱歉
first method we're going to write is
我们要写的第一种方法是
going to be our init method so define
将成为我们的init 方法，如此定义
underscore underscore init underscore
下划线下划线init下划线
underscore whoops just do and then we're
强调哎呦，然后我们
just going to self and then we're gonna
只是去自我，然后我们会
have orgs which is just kind of like an
有 机构单位这仅仅是 一种像一个
arbitrary number
任意 数量
added keyword arguments and the first
添加了关键字参数和第一个
thing we're going to do is super and
我们要做的事情是超级和
we're going to super the login screen
我们要超级登录屏幕
cell and then dot underscore underscore
单元格 ，然后点下划线下划线
init underscore underscore and then
init强调下划线然后
asterisk asterisk kwargs okay so
星号星号kwargs好吧
basically what this is going to do is so
基本上这是怎么 做的
we don't actually have to reference our
我们实际上并不需要 引用我们的
base class okay so this will allow us to
基类好， 所以这 将使我们能够
kind of use multi inheritance rather
有点用多重继承
than just you know grid layout so define
不仅仅是你知道网格布局如此定义
in it Oh
在里面哦
basically our init class does that then
基本上我们的init类就是这么做的
we're going to say self dots
我们要说自己的点
uh calls for columns equals we're going
呃呼吁列等于 我们要去
to say two and then we're going to say
说两个，然后我们会 说
self dot add underscore widget and the
自我点添加下划线小部件和
widget we're going to add is this label
我们要添加的小部件就是这个标签
widget right up here and so the label
小部件在这里等标签
widget and within that we're going to
小部件和我们要做的
say the text equals lost my mouth there
说文字等于在 那里 失去了我的 嘴
we go
我们去
username okay so that's our first widget
用户名好，所以这是我们的 第一个小部件
now you might be able to guess now what
现在你可以 猜测现在是什么
might come next is but we need the the
可能接下来是但我们需要的
next widget which is basically a text
下一个基本上是文本的小部件
input widget so now we will say self dot
输入小部件，所以现在我们会说自我点
username and that's obviously going to
用户名，这显然会
be referencing whatever they type in
引用他们输入的内容
here so how do we reference that well
在这里，我们如何参考这个好
we're going to say self dot using equals
我们将使用equals来说自己的点
text input referencing this so text
文本输入引用这个文本
input and then we're going to say
输入，然后我们会说
multi-line equals false and this is
多线等于错误， 这是
because it's not a paragraph here is a
因为这不是一个段落
single username so we don't need many
单个用户名， 所以我们不需要很多
lines here so multi-line equals false
这里的多行代码等于false
and then we can say self dot add
然后我们可以说自己点 添加
underscore with JIT and now we want to
用JIT强调，现在我们想要
add the widget of self dot username and
添加自我点用户名和小部件
that's basically it for adding a
这基本上是 为了添加一个
username so I think we should be able to
用户名，所以我认为我们应该能够
get away with running this real quick
逃避这种真正的快速运行
and see where we stand we'll see sure
看看我们的立场，我们会看到肯定
enough there we go we have a username
足够我们去我们有一个用户名
and if we click in here we can already
如果我们点击这里，我们 已经 可以
are typing in our text appears so again
正在 我们的文字 中输入 再次出现
all of those things kind of happen for
所有 这些事情都会 发生
us and it's because it's not multi-line
我们这是因为它 不是多线的
you could hit enter and we are actually
你可以打进来，我们 其实是
outside now of this text box when we hit
当我们 击中 时，在这个文本框的外面
enter so cool so anyways we can close
进入 这么酷， 所以我们可以关闭
this close this and now let's go ahead
这关闭了， 现在 让我们继续
let's like add a couple more things so
让我们来添加一些更多的 东西
we have two columns but basically we can
我们有两列，但 基本上可以
continue adding new widgets so we could
继续添加新的小部件， 这样我们就可以
in theory let's just try this let's copy
理论上我们只是试试这个让我们来复制
this and our enter paste and now let's
这和我们输入粘贴，现在让我们来
say this is password self dot password
说这是密码 自我点密码
equals that copy password paste it here
等于该复制密码粘贴在这里
and now let us save and run that and so
现在让我们保存并运行它 等等
now you have your username is a sent X
现在你有你的 用户名 是发送X.
and your password
和你的密码
oops int X and your password is awesome
oops int X 和你的密码真棒
oh no our password is actually showing
哦，不，我们的密码 实际上是显示
the text so that's kind of a problem huh
那么这段文字就有点问题了吧
how do we write some code to solve that
我们 如何 编写一些代码 来解决这个问题
well TVs done that for you
好电视为你做
so when you come down here you got
所以当你在 这里 下来时你就会得到
multi-line equals false we can actually
实际上多行等于假我们可以
just add another parameter here
只需在此添加另一个参数
multi-line equals false password equals
多行等于false密码等于
true it's just a parameter in a text
它只是一个文本中 的参数
input and password equals true what it's
输入和密码等于真正的东西
going to do is just make your password
要做的只是让你的密码
asterisks so now we can save and run
星号，所以现在我们可以保存并运行
that and username again can be syntax
那个和用户名可以是语法
and then I keep on to hit tab as I'm
然后我继续 打标签为我
expecting it to work anyway password is
无论如何，期待它工作密码是
awesome but you don't see its asterisks
真棒， 但你看不到它的星号
now so pretty cool so now um actually
现在 非常酷，所以 现在实际上呢
I'm a little curious see if we can copy
我有点好奇， 看看我们是否可以复制
this if come down here paste oh they are
这个如果 来这里粘贴哦，他们 是
aspis okay cool anyway uh moving on so
无论如何，无论如何，无论如何，无论如何，都可以
you got username password I mean this
你的用户名密码是我的意思
the list could go on right so we could
名单可以继续下去，所以我们可以
say we get another one we could say self
说我们可以得到另一个我们可以说自己
dot add the widgets a two factor auth
点添加小部件 一个双因素 认证
right so your two-factor authentication
对你的 双因素认证
we don't need to leave the password bar
我们不需要离开密码栏
there and then we can say TF a so we
那里，然后我们可以说TF一个， 所以我们
can't do
做不到
2fa but anyway TFA save and run that and
2fa但无论如何 TFA保存并运行该和
now you've got you know username
现在你已经知道了用户名
password two-factor off you can enter
你可以输入 密码 双因素
all that we don't really have a login
所有 我们并没有登录的人
button but well I guess we can talk
按钮，但我想我们可以谈谈
about that and a little bit so that
关于一点点， 这样
those just like you know some basics to
这些就像你知道的一些基础知识
creating some simple input some simple
创建一些简单输入一些简单的
interactivity and just like before we've
交互性，就像之前一样
actually coded quite or we've got an
实际编码相当或我们有 一个
application that requires quite a bit of
应用程序需要 相当多 的
code but since kV does most of the work
代码，但由于千伏大部分的 工作
for us we don't really need to write
对我们来说， 我们并不需要写作
that much I mean most of this code is
我的意思是 这个 代码的 大部分 是
actually fairly redundant right this all
其实相当多余的权利这一切
this is pretty much just copy and paste
这 几乎 只是 复制和粘贴
we change the label a little bit but for
我们稍微改变了一下标签，但是为了
the most part I mean this isn't really
我的意思是大部分并不是 真的
that complex yet we've made it pretty
这个复杂的，但我们已经做得很好
you know I mean the window itself that
你 知道 我的意思是窗户本身
we created is pretty simplistic but the
我们创造的非常简单，但是
amount of code required in the true
真正需要的代码量
back-end right if we look at all the
后端权利，如果我们看看所有 的
code involved in text input and grid
代码涉及文本输入和网格
layout and label and key V dot app which
布局和标签和关键 V点应用程序
we've already seen and I think I showed
我们已经看到了，我想我已经展示过了
label in the previous video it's a lot
在以前的视频标签很多
of code so it saves you a lot of time
的代码，因此可以节省 您很多 时间
and it's definitely nice for rapid
这对于快速而言 绝对 不错
development so anyway that's it for this
无论如何发展，就是这样
video if you have any questions or
视频如果你有 任何 问题或
comments please feel free to leave them
评论请随时 离开他们
below otherwise as always thanks for
一如以往感谢
watching thanks for all the support
感谢所有的支持
subscriptions and it's till the next
订阅，直到下一个
video
视频